[Music]
let's add up the first four perfect
squares
one plus four plus nine plus sixteen
by arranging the l-shaped nomens from
each of this square
we get this tower which consists of a
one by seven
a two by 5 a 3 by 3 and a 4 by 1 stack
of squares
we can then use the sum of squares twice
more
to build a rectangle
notice that this rectangle has width two
times four
plus one
and the length of this rectangle is one
plus two plus three
plus four therefore we see that 3 times
the sum of the first four squares
is 2 times 4 plus 1 multiplied by the
sum of the first four positive integers
there's nothing special about four
squares the analogous geometric
construction will work for the sum of
the first
n squares showing that three times the
sum of the first n squares
is two n plus one multiplied by the sum
of the first n positive integers
applying a known sum formula for the sum
of integers
and then dividing by 3 yields a formula
for the sum of the first
n squares